《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
我是纳撒尼尔·巴恩斯
My name is Nathaniel Barnes.
我是你们的新上司
I'm your new boss.
希德·邦德斯洛
Sid Bunderslaw.
我是操作部主管
I'm the Director of Physical Operations.
我一直在等你
I've been expecting you.
加勒特  平克尼  乔茜  马丁纳兹
Garrett! Pinkney! Josie! Martinez!
恭喜
Congratulations.
你们现在是哥谭市警局第一突击队的成员了
You are now Unit Alpha of the GCPD Strike Force
奥斯瓦尔德·科波特/企鹅
该扳倒企鹅了
Time to take down The Penguin.
母亲
Mother.
你们会付出代价的
You'll pay for this.
请投给霍布斯
这些人死了  你母亲就可以活
They die, your mother lives.
詹妮丝·考菲尔德竞选市长
我需要你也对我下手
And I'm gonna need you to take a crack at me also.
当然你得失手
And miss, of course.
趴下
Get down!
如果坏人想要阻止我竞选
If the bad guys want to stop me running,
那我想我也别无选择了
well, then I guess I got no choice.
我会竞选市长一职
I will run for mayor.
谢谢你送来箱子  老朋友
Thank you for the trunk, old friend.
我有需要时会打电话找你的
I'll call you when I need you.
我很高兴你把我称作朋友
I'm glad you call me a friend.
只是个说法而已
Figure of speech.
但你继续说吧
But do go on.
我不禁想...
I can't help feeling...
我作为你的朋友不是更有价值吗
wouldn't I be so much more useful to you as a friend?
或是你的同伙  同盟
As a colleague, an ally?
而不是现在的工具吗
As opposed to the tool you are at present.
好问题
Good question.
不行
No.
我可以成为更有用的工具
I would be a much more effective tool for you
如果我不必担心我母亲的话
if I wasn't so worried about my mother.
如果你放她回家
If you let her come home,
我仍会听从你的命令
I would still do your bidding.
相信我  我现在知道谁是老大了
Trust me, I know who's boss now.
发发慈悲吧
Lord have mercy.
没必要戳人痛处
No need to rub it in.
没错  先生  我们都知道谁是老大
Yes, sir, we all know who's boss.
你认为呢  塔比莎
What do you think, Tabitha?
我没在听
I wasn't listening.
你知道我多喜欢大块头的男人
You know how I love the big macho type.
别去招他
Leave him alone.
是啊  别来招我
Yeah, leave me alone.
答案是不行
The answer is no,
老朋友
old friend.
你可以走了
Off you go.
守着电话
Stay by the phone.
你别吓唬帮手好吗
I wish you wouldn't freak out the help.
我还要竞选市长呢
I've got a mayoral campaign to run.
我要知道你能处理好这块事务
I need to know your gonna handle this part of the business.
我无聊嘛
I get bored.
我讨厌你那么讲  你有很多事可做
I hate it when you say that. You have plenty to do.
你还能玩弄詹姆斯市长呢
You still have Mayor James to play with.
他在这里都快一个月了
He's been here nearly a month.
越来越没劲了
He's getting old fast.
芭芭拉也可以陪你
You got Barbara to hang out with.
她很棒  但她老睡觉
Yeah, she's cool, but she sleeps a lot.
她还有点疯狂
And she's kind of crazy.
那是她最棒之处
That's the best part about her.
盖勒文
Galavan?
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
邦德斯洛先生  欢迎
Mr. Bunderslaw, welcome.
你想拿我怎样
What... what do you want with me?
你是韦恩集团的"清洁工"  对吗
You are the garbage man for Wayne Enterprises, correct?
公司所做的所有丑事
Every nasty little thing the company has done,
你都知道
you know all about it.
-不是  -是的
- No. - Yes,
并且你要告诉我们
and you are gonna tell us
你知道的一切
everything that you know.
如果我拒绝呢
And if I refuse?
那只能严刑逼供了
Torture.
但那是之后的事了
But that's for later.
现在  我们需要跟你借个东西
Right now, there is something of yours we need to borrow.
妹妹  麻烦了
Sister, if you don't mind.
左边还是右边
Left or right?
都行
Either one.
不要...
No...
哥谭
第二季  第五集
25乘25个箱子
25 and 25 boxes.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 小胖纸不想做小胖纸   charcie   DustD   盐湖凉开水
翻译 Silence   辰星晓Reginamoon   小酸奶!   大K   木浅   草草
时间轴 风吹来的那片云
后期 宝宝   校对 草草   总监 草草
天呐...
God...!
不想吃枪子的
Anybody who doesn't want to get shot,
举起手来
raise your hand!
趴下
Get down!
还有火箭筒
A damn rocket launcher?
欢迎来到哥谭  警监
Welcome to Gotham, Cap.
这一沓子就是我的年薪了
I can fit my yearly salary in my hands.
别对这些钱打什么主意  小子
Don't get any ideas about that cash, son.
都装好
Just bag it up.
别担心  长官
Don't worry, sir.
他没什么主意的
Ideas aren't his strong suit.
我大概算了一下  长官
Did some rough calculations, sir.
这里有大概二百万美金
Somewhere around two million dollars here.
这对企鹅来说是拳重击
It's a strong body blow to Penguin.
他会感觉到的
He'll feel it.
长官
Sir?
他们想要裤子
They're asking for their pants.
给他们宣读权利
Read 'em their rights.
里面根本没提裤子
Doesn't say squat about pants.
等等
Wait.
告诉他们提供火箭筒来源的人
Tell 'em the whoever gives up where they got the damn rocket launcher
就能穿裤子
gets to wear pants.
其余的就裸着吧  我才不管
The rest can go naked, for all I care.
警监
Captain.
说句话
A word?
有个地方叫佣兵商场
There's a place called the Merc.
大多重型武器那儿都有卖
Sells most of the heavy weapons in town.
他们还没被查过
They haven't been hit,
因为他们买通了半个市议会
'cause they pay off half the city council.
佣兵商场是吧
The Merc, uh?
去他的市议会
The city council can suck my tailpipe.
咱们明天就突袭佣兵商场
We're gonna hit this Merc tomorrow.
平克尼  命令收回
Pinkney, belay that order.
谁都不准穿裤子
No one gets pants.
我们去抓他
We grab him up.
抓回来  往死里折磨
We grab him, and we hurt him
直到他说出她在哪  然后再继续折磨
until he tells us where she is, and then we hurt him more.
这主意好吗
Okay, is that a good idea?
你有更好的主意吗
Do you have a better one?
抓他妹妹
We could get the sister.
然后呢
And then what?
他照样逍遥自在
He's still out there,
他对他妹妹的爱能比过我对我母亲的爱吗
and does he love his sister as much as I love my mother?
绝不可能
I don't think so!
的确是难题
It is a pickle.
企鹅先生
Mr. Penguin, sir,
警察刚袭击了点钞房
the cops just hit the count house.
他们拿走了所有钱  一分不剩
They took everything, every dollar.
告诉我这消息你还挺高兴是吧
Did you enjoy giving me that news?!
布奇
Butch!
我有个主意
I have an idea.
你好啊
Hey, you.
早上好
Good morning.
今天怎么样
How's your day look?
突击队今天又要去进行突袭
The strike force is going out on another raid.
突击队
Strike force.
我讨厌这名字
I hate that name.
我也不是太喜欢
Yeah, I'm not wild about it myself,
但是巴恩斯能办成事
but Barnes gets things done.
他想叫什么都行
He can call us what he likes.
好吧  那么你和突击队去突击
All right, so you go strike with your force,
晚上回来后咱们干什么
then what are we doing tonight?
-睡觉  -不行  今晚是约会之夜  先生
- Sleep. - Uh-uh, it's date night, mister.
和谁
With who?
早安  爱德
Morning, Ed.
警探  汤普金斯小姐
Detective, Ms. Thompkins.
正如你们所知  我最近在和柯林格小姐约会
As you may have heard, I've recently been seeing Miss Kringle.
柯丽丝汀
Kristen.
而她建议
And she mentioned
和其他人一起出去比较好
that it might be nice to go out with other people along,
所以我想  不知你们两人愿不愿
so I thought, perhaps, the two of you would enjoy
今晚和我们共进晚餐
joining us for dinner tonight.
-我们不行  -我们很乐意
- We can't. - We'd love to.
好吧
Sure.
行  行啊  太好了
Yeah, yeah, no. Great.
事实上  我刚买了奶酪火锅
As a matter of fact, I just bought some new fondue pots.
咱们去我家吃怎么样
Why don't we do it at my house?
好极了  好极了
Excellent, excellent.
我去和柯丽丝汀说
I'll go tell Kristen.
我知道  我知道  但这样做才像样
I know, I know, but it was the decent thing to do.
奶酪火锅
Fondue?
你吃过吗  可好吃了
Have you ever tried it? It's delicious.
那是在你家里
It's at your place.
我们又不能借口离开
We can't leave.
咱们已经在家了
We're already home.
-被困住了  -别那么凶嘛
- Trapped. - Don't be mean.
想办法找找乐子呗
We'll make it fun.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
早上好
Good morning.
我们能不能  单独谈谈
I wonder if we could, uh, talk alone?
当然可以
Of course.
谢谢你能抽出宝贵时间
Thank you for, uh, giving me some of your valuable time.
没什么
Not a problem.
晚会那晚  我...
That night at the gala, I...
我一直在回想
I just keep going through it.
我也是
Me, too.
我之前从没杀过人
I've never killed a man before.
恐惧  鲜血
Fear... blood...
我一遍遍地重温那一刻
I relive that moment over and over.
这些念头会消失吗
Do those thoughts ever go away?
不会
No.
但时间久了  就没那么强烈了
But over time, they lose their power.
你做的是对的
You did the right thing.
也许吧
I guess I did.
我都觉得不可思议
I'm kind of amazed at myself.
而你  一直在做正确的事  这是
You, doing the right thing, it's what you do
你的日常工作
every day.
所以大家对你的评价才那么高
That's why people speak so highly of you.
你对这座城市的人民  是一个符号
You're a symbol to the people of this city--
象征了希望  和荣誉
of hope, of honor.
所以我今天才来找你
That's why I'm here.
如果你能考虑
I would be honored...
为我的市长竞选背书
if you would consider...
我将不胜荣幸
endorsing me for mayor.
背书啊
Endorsement.
我很荣幸
I'm flattered, but, uh,
但恐怕警察和政客不太搭
I'm afraid policemen and politics don't mix.
巡警或许如此
Maybe not for the cop on the street,
但你还是警察工会的主席
but you're the president of the Policeman's Union.
你的号召  警员们都会响应
Where you lead, officers will follow.
这种力量
That's more power
可不是武力能达到的
than the kind that comes out of a gun.
我觉得你是个好人
You seem like a good man,
但是
but...
我恐怕只能拒绝你了
I'm afraid my answer has to be no.
我不搞背书
I don't do endorsements.
我知道逼你也没用
I know better than to push.
但还是考虑一下吧
But think about it.
我们真的能帮助彼此
We could really help each other.
你好  企鹅
Hi, Penguin.
有事吗
What do you want?
干吗这么阴郁
Why so glum?
我刚丢了一大笔钱
I just lost a lot of money.
可怜的小东西
Poor sad little bread head.
钱不重要
The money is immaterial.
重要的是有人背叛了我
Someone must have betrayed me.
我亲近的人
Someone close.
这可不一定  老大
You don't know that, boss.
不一定吗
Oh, don't I?
Don't I?!
镇定  鸟人
Chill, birdman.
我有活儿要交给你
I got a job for you.
那是什么
What's that?
你得去烧为平地的地址
Addresses of places you're gonna burn to the ground.
今晚就开始
Starting tonight.
又要纵火啦
Arson now?
好吧  可以
Sure, fine.
随便了
Whatever.
如果我能找到值得信任的纵火犯的话
If I can find a trustworthy arsonist.
真是疑神疑鬼啊
Paranoid, huh?
振作一点  小子
Get your head together, little man,
把事办好
and get it done.
对了  不管谁去放火  他会需要这个
Oh, and whoever starts the fires is gonna need this.
地方不错啊
Nice place.
有事吗
Whassup?
我需要你带我去找派克兄弟
I need you to take me to the Pike Brothers.
那几个奈何岛的纵火犯吗
The firebugs from the Narrows?
我小时候跟他们的小妹布莉姬特一起玩过
I used to hang with their sister, Bridgit, when I was a kid.
为什么要我带你去
Why do you need me to take you?
你要替我担保
To vouch for me.
派克兄弟是城里最专业的纵火犯
The Pikes are the best arsonists in town,
但他们也是菲什的忠诚追随者
but they're also Fish loyalists.
这帮白痴以为她有一天会卷土重来呢
The idiots think she's coming back someday.
有可能的
She might come back.
我当时就在现场  亲爱的
I was there, darlin'.
-我是说可能  -随便吧
- She might. - Whatever.
派克兄弟不喜欢我和企鹅
The Pikes hate me and Penguin,
原因就不用说了  但是
for obvious reasons, but...
大家都知道菲什喜欢你
everyone knows Fish loved you.
是吗
They do?
你的脸就是门路啊  宝贝
Your face will open doors, babe.
六百块
Six hundred.
三百五
Three-fifty.
成交
Fine.
让我跟他们说
Just let me do the talkin'.
你在一边陪笑  假装我们是朋友就好
You just smile and make like we're friends.
朋友
Friends?
那还得再加一百
That's a hundred extra.
真刁
Chiseler.
那么  大家都知道菲什喜欢我吗
So, everybody knows she loved me?
大家都这么说
That's what they say.
她曾经也喜欢我
She loved me, too, once.
我也爱她
And I loved her.
然后你杀了她
Then you shot her.
事情很复杂
It was complicated.
这是没错
Got that right.
布莉姬特  你好
Hi, Bridgit.
塞琳娜
Selina.
好久不见
It's been a while.
我跟我的宠物大猩猩是来谈生意的
Me and my pet gorilla are here on business.
你三个哥哥在家吗
Your brothers home?
是的
Yeah.
你们好啊
Hey, boys.
你跟这叛徒在一起做什么  塞琳娜
What are you doing with this rat, Selina?
他没问题
He's okay.
我替他担保
I vouch for him.
什么叫"没问题"
What do you mean, okay?
这混蛋杀了菲什
The bastard shot Fish.
事情很复杂
It was complicated.
他跟你们一样爱她
He loves her just like you do.
如果她有一日能卷土重来...
And if she ever comes back...
她肯定能卷土重来
When she comes back.
到那时候
When she does,
他马上就会回到她身边
he will be right by her side.
如果她卷土重来
If she comes back?
好吧  但是她
Sure. But she...
但是今天  他有个好差事给你们
But right now, he got a nice job for you guys.
生意归生意嘛
Business is business, right?
既往不咎了吧
Bygones, huh?
我们需要最好的  而你们正巧就是
We need the best, and you guys are the best.
别激动
Easy.
活儿挺多啊
That's a lot of work.
报酬也不少
A lot of pay.
你们愿意干吗
You up for it?
当然
For sure.
我们需要更多装备  我去趟佣兵商场备点货
We'll need more gear. I'll hit the Merc and stock up.
我们的装备都足够把哥谭烧平两次了
We've got enough gear to burn down Gotham twice.
凝固汽油总是不嫌多的
There's always room for more napalm.
谢谢
Thanks.
妹妹
Hey, sis...
你怎么这么懒
what are you, a slob?
有客人在
We have company.
有客人在时我们要怎么做
What do we do when we have company?
给客人拿个杯子
We get them a glass.
没错  快去拿
Ding, ding, ding. Go and do it.
谢谢你  布莉姬特
Thank you, Bridgit.
你们会需要这个
You're gonna need this.
好像下雨了
Looks like rain.
是啊
Yeah, it does.
我不介意
I don't mind it.
至少能清洗街道
Cleans the streets anyhow.
那倒是
That's true.
总之
Anyway, um,
你保重  布莉姬特
take care of yourself, Bridgit.
坚强点
Be strong.
能否查看一下
Yeah, can we get a price check
毒绿铁莲花的价格
on brass knuckles in toxic green?
三百就行
300 gets it done.
票子脏了要多收10%
Uh, 10% surcharge for soiled bills.
谢谢你
Thank you kindly.
试试我们的一吹倒
Try our Whiff-Away.
现在第七货架上有售
On sale now in Aisle Seven.
欢迎来到佣兵商场  砍刀
Welcome to Merc, your one-stop shop
夜视镜  以及所有
for machetes, night-vision goggles,
个人防卫所需物品一应俱全
and all of your personal defense needs.
炸药
抢劫喽
Robbery.
咬嘴和消声器
...mouthpiece and muzzle guard.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
大家都趴下
Everybody on the ground!
突袭
This is a raid!
有人跑了
Runner!
我去追
I got him!
站住
Stop!
立刻给我站住
Stop right now!
你用的什么子弹啊
What the hell are you packing?
奶酪融化时  蛋白基质松动
When cheese melts, the protein matrix relaxes
脂肪就会更像液体
and the fats flow more like liquid.
从而产生低摩擦口感
It creates this low-friction mouth feel,
所以融化奶酪才如此...
which is why melted cheese is so...
爱德
Ed.
很美味
Uh, it's delicious.
是的  没错
Yes, it is.
糟糕
Oh, no!
小莱  我们不应该不等吉姆就开吃的
Oh, Lee, we shouldn't be eating without Jim here.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
不不  请吧  吃吧  没关系的
No, no, no, please, eat. It's fine.
他来了
There he is.
你好啊
Hello, there.
好啊  吉姆  很高兴见到你
Hey, Jim. Nice to see you.
对不起我迟到了
Sorry I'm late.
真的很抱歉
Really sorry.
说来话长
Long story.
希望没有很糟糕
I hope it hasn't been going too bad.
知道吗  说来奇怪
You know, it's the weirdest thing,
但尼格玛还真有种奇怪的酷劲儿
but Nygma's actually maintaining this strange sort of cool.
不会吧
No.
真的
Seriously.
各花入各眼啊
There's a lid for every pot.
抱歉
Pardon me.
既然戈登警探到了
Since Detective Gordon is here,
我想敬杯酒
I'd like to propose a toast.
拥有的越少
The less you have,
就越珍贵
the more they're worth.
敬朋友
To friends.
说得好
Hear, hear.
我不能相信他死了
I can't believe he's dead.
我们这辈子最大的一票
Biggest job of our lives,
却发生了这种事
and this happens.
我们怎么办
So what do we do?
毫无疑问  我们得干这一票
For sure, we do the job.
怎么干  我们死定了
How? We're screwed.
现在谁进去呢
Who's our entry man now?
谁从排气口爬进去  谁攀逃生梯
Crawling through air vents? Climbing fire escapes?
我们需要个小瘦猴
We need a little skinny guy.
你觉得呢
You think?
布莉姬
Hey, Bridgy...
你刚刚升职了
you just got a promotion.
不要
No.
要
Yes.
求你了  你知道我不喜欢火的
Please, you know I don't like fire.
你不喜欢火吗
You don't like fire?
火是我们的生计
Fire is our bread and butter.
这是我们的家族生意
It's our family business.
你不想让你的家人失望吧
You're don't want to let down your family, do you?
你们不是我的家人
You're not my family.
什么
What's that?
我们不是你的家人
We're not your family?
你还有别人吗
You got anybody else?
我妈妈...
My mother...
你妈是个婊子  而且她已经死了
Your mother was a ho, and she's dead.
谁养你的  谁给你地方住
Who feeds you? Who puts a roof above your head? Huh?
是我们
We do.
那就是家人
That's family.
我不会去的
I won't do it.
好  就这样吧
Fine, be like that.
但如果你不是家人
But if you're not family,
那一切都变了
well, that changes things around here, though.
我是个正派的人
See, I'm a decent guy.
我绝对不会让家人去站街
I would never put family on the street.
但如果你不是家人
But if you're not family...
管他呢...
hell...
为什么不趁此捞一笔
why not make a buck?
这主意太棒了
Yo, that's a kick-ass idea.
你准备怎么办
So what are you gonna do?
你是想出去卖
Do you want to be turned out?
还是想做家人
Or do you want to be family?
选哪个
Which?
家人
Family.
他想让我背书他做市长
He wanted me to endorse him for Mayor.
你怎么说的
What did you say?
我说不行
I said no.
你不喜欢他吗
You don't like him?
其实我挺喜欢他的
I do, actually.
但是我知道这不是借口
But I know better than to let that matter.
背书政客...
Endorsing politicians--
不是我的做法
that's not me.
但他问你了  还是说明他很看得起你
Still, he asked you. That's very flattering.
说明你在本市非常受人尊敬
You're a respected figure in this  respected figure .
人们看待你的方式
The way people look at you,
发生了改变
see you differently,
你觉得这是一种负担
you treat it like it's a burden.
但如果你想的话  这可以是一种骄傲
It could be a source of pride, or happiness even,
甚至是幸福
if you let it.
谢谢  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
下周同一时间吧
Same time next week?
不要诱惑我  我可以把你分析得透透彻彻
Don't tempt me. I could psychoanalyze the heck out of you.
但我会抑制住这种冲动的
But I'm gonna resist the urge.
天  多谢了
Gee, thanks.
坚强点  布莉姬特
Be strong, Bridgit.
好了
Okay.
装上去了
It's on.
现在  你要剪一段
Now...you're gonna want to cut yourself
长约45厘米的引线
about a foot and a half of fuse.
好了
Okay.
把引线塞到塑料炸弹里
Push the wick into the plastic explosive.
好了
Okay.
现在点上火
Now get out the flame.
点燃引线后  你大概有1分半的时间
You got about a minute and a half to get out of there
离开那个地方
once that fuse is lit.
点吧
Spark it up.
点着了
It's lit.
好
Okay, great.
不好意思  还有一件事
Sorry, there's one more thing to do.
但已经点着了
But it's lit!
那你最好快点
Well, you'd better haul ass.
你看到右方的保险柜了吗
Do you see a safe on your right?
看到了
Yeah.
去那边
Get to it.
好
Okay.
到了
好  拿起放在包底的盒子
Okay, now grab the box at the bottom of the bag
把盒子打开
and open it up.
我的天
Oh, my God.
恶心吧
Grody, right?
把它放在门边的传感器前
Okay, put it to the sensor next to the door.
欢迎你  邦德斯洛先生
Welcome, Mr. Bunderslaw.
好了
Okay.
打开了  然后呢
It's open. Now what?
乔
Joe?
乔  你在哪里
Joe, where are you?
乔  怎么了
Joe, what's wrong?
我逗你玩呢
I'm just messing with you.
那里有把古董刀  拿走
Okay, so there should be an old knife there. Grab it.
好了
Okay.
拿到了
Got it.
好  现在...
Okay, now...
赶紧出来
scram.
好样的
Attagirl.
干得漂亮  妹妹
You did good, sis.
快上车  快点
Get in the van, chop chop.
我腿烧伤了
I burned my leg.
没听过"玩火者必自焚"嘛
Well, "You play with fire, you get burned," all of that.
我们今晚还得干四票
We got four more of these to do tonight,
赶紧给我上车
so get in the damn van.
五个地方  全都被烧毁了
Five locations, all burned to the ground.
怎么了  加勒特
Yeah, Garrett?
打扰了  长官
Excuse me, sir.
鉴证科打来说  纵火犯使用的是
Lab called in, said the fires were started
铝热剂和高端助燃剂
with thermite and high-end accelerants.
这么说  纵火犯是群行家
So we're looking for professional arsonists.
谢谢
Thanks.
加勒特  昨天表现不错
And, Garrett, nice work yesterday.
谢谢  长官
Thank you, sir.
奇怪
Strange.
专业纵火犯为什么会一晚上干五票
Why would a pro do five jobs in one night?
怎么这么急
What's the rush?
如果他们还没完事呢
And what if they're not done?
找出五场火灾的共通点
Find a pattern to these fires.
别等他们把整座城都给烧了
Before they burn down the whole city.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
做件防火服  这样我就不会再被烧伤了
Making a suit, so I won't get burned again.
你怎么会再被烧伤呢
Why would you get burned again?
他们开始让你放火了吗
So they're making you start the fires?
是吧
I guess.
坐吧  想喝饮料吗
Sit down. You want a soda or something?
不了  我要把那个拿给企鹅
No, I-I can't, I'm supposed to take that to Penguin.
好吧
Okay.
你这样下去  会早晚没命的
You know, you're gonna get yourself killed.
我会小心的
I'll be careful.
光小心是不够的
Well, careful ain't enough.
还不是被烧伤了
Look what happened already.
昨晚挺刺激的  塞琳娜
It was exciting, Selina.
我其实挺喜欢的
I actually kind of enjoyed it.
嗯  你肯定会变成烤肉的
Yep, you're gonna be bacon.
我哥哥说我干得不错
My brother said I did a good job.
这是家族生意
It's the family business.
他们不是你的家人
They're not your family.
你妈妈以前上过他们爸爸
Your mom used to bang their old man
仅此而已
is all.
你不需要他们
You don't need them.
你谁都不需要
You don't need anybody.
看我啊  我多自由
Look at me-- I'm free.
我记得我小时候  你跑来奈何岛
I remember when I was little and you showed up at the Narrows.
天天来找你妈妈
You looked for your mom every day.
哭得一把鼻涕一把泪
Snot all down your face from crying.
被装作你不想要个家庭
So don't act like you don't want a family.
别提我妈妈
Don't talk about my mom.
你自由又怎么样
Who cares if you're free?
你如果孤零零一个人自由有什么用
What good's freedom if you're alone?
你如果是个奴隶家人有什么用
What good's family if you're a slave?
随你吧
Whatever.
真不知道你为什么觉得我在乎
I don't even know why you think I care.
没道理
Doesn't make any sense.
这是韦恩家族的族徽
This is the Wayne family crest.
怎么了
So what?
盖勒文为什么要一把
Why does Galavan want an antique knife
属于韦恩家族的古董刀
that belonged to the Waynes?
这里面有问题
There's something here,
能让我理解盖勒文  打败他的东西
something to understanding Galavan, to beating him.
如果你想了解哥谭旧事  就问艾德维奇
Well, if you want to know about old-time Gotham, talk to Edwige.
谁
Edwige?
嗯  她在我以前街区开家古董店
Yeah. She runs the antique shop in my old neighborhood.
相信我
Trust me.
她知道很多事
She knows things.
你可以拿起来看看
You can pick it up if you like.
不用了
That's okay.
抱歉
Sorry.
我帮不了你
I can't help you.
艾德维奇
Edwige,
我看得出你认得那把刀
I can see that you know this knife.
你怕这把刀
You're scared of this knife.
为什么
Why?
-你为什么跟我撒谎  -我没有
- Why are you lying to me? - I'm not.
女士  我最不会看错的  就是撒谎者了
Madam, if there's one thing I know, it's a liar.
跟我讲讲这把刀的事
Now, tell me about this knife,
否则我就用它杀了你
or I will use it.
这把刀有一段被诅咒的历史
This knife has a cursed history.
将近两百年前  它被用来犯下了可怕的罪过
Almost 200 years ago, it was used in a terrible crime.
当时
Back then...
哥谭上流社会由五大家族统治
five families ruled Gotham high society.
艾略特家族  凯恩家族
The Elliots, the Kanes,
克朗家族  杜马家族
the Crownes, the Dumas...
以及最有权势的  韦恩家族
and the most powerful of them all-- the Waynes.
他们将瑟莱斯汀·韦恩
They called Celestine Wayne
称作哥谭的皇冠之珠
the crown jewel of Gotham.
美的倾国倾城
A real beauty.
她本已订婚
She was promised
对象是艾略特家族的长子
to the eldest son of the Elliot family.
但还有一人也觊觎她
But there was another who coveted her.
凯勒布·杜马
Caleb Dumas.
有一晚
One night...
那是在韦恩庄园的复活节派对上
it was during an Easter party at the Wayne Manor...
瑟莱斯汀和凯勒布不知所踪
Celestine and Caleb went missing.
韦恩家的人发现两人在偷欢
Wayne men found them together in an illicit embrace.
-我们相爱了  -凯勒布坚称两人是相爱的
- We're in love! - Caleb insisted that they were in love and...
瑟莱斯汀则以她母亲的坟墓起誓
Celestine swore on her mother's grave
说是凯勒布强奸了她
that Caleb had forced himself on her.
-我是无辜的  瑟莱斯汀  -很快
- I'm innocent. Celestine! - Justice,
-我说的是真的  -正义就得以伸张
- I'm telling the truth! - if that's what it was,
-瑟莱斯汀  -如果那是正义的话
- Celestine! - was swift.
瑟莱斯汀的哥哥乔纳森·韦恩施予了惩罚
Celestine's brother Jonathan Wayne delivered the punishment.
韦恩一家
The Waynes...
愤怒得发狂
they were mad with rage.
他们侵占了杜马家的股份  把他们逐出社会
They seized the Dumas' holdings and banished them socially,
毁了他们
destroyed them.
凯勒布·杜马
Caleb Dumas
被流放去了海外
went into exile overseas,
与他家族的守护圣徒
to a penitential religious sect
建立的一派赎罪教派待在一起
founded by his family's patron saint.
瑟莱斯汀至死未嫁
Celestine died an old maid.
韦恩家族不许媒体
The Waynes forbade the press
提及杜马一家
from even mentioning the Dumas.
他们更改了街道  建筑的名字
They renamed streets and buildings.
杜马家族剩下的人
The remnants of the Dumas family
都被迫改名
were forced to change their name.
韦恩家族将杜马家族
The Waynes wiped the Dumas
从我们城市的历史中抹了去
out of our city's history.
杜马家族剩余的人
Those remnants of the Dumas family...
他们把名字改成什么了
to what did they change their name?
你真聪明
Aren't you quick?
盖勒文
Galavan.
他们改叫盖勒文了
They changed their name to Galavan.
就像那个竞选市长的家伙
Just like that fella runnin' for mayor.
所以我怕这把刀
And that's why I'm scared of this knife.
你淌进深水了  企鹅先生
You're in deep waters, Mr. Penguin.
谢谢你  艾德维奇
Thank you, Edwige.
企鹅就在水里最自在了
That is where penguins thrive.
你听说任何关于大火的事都来见我
You hear anything about any fires, you come see me,
为自己赢得一张免死金牌  好吗
earn yourself a "Get out of jail free" card, all right?
你脸上有那副表情
You got a look on your face.
虽然都被小心隐藏在一堆公司化名之下
It's well hidden behind a bunch of corporate aliases,
但昨晚被烧毁的大楼
but all the buildings that burned down last night,
业主都是一个人
they have one landlord:
韦恩集团
Wayne Enterprises.
纵火犯从东向西走
The arsonists moved east to west.
如果他们今晚再出来  而且还是这个走向
If they come out tonight and stick to pattern,
那么有个明显的目标
there's one obvious target,
一栋韦恩集团名下的老楼
an old building also owned by Wayne Enterprises--
哥谭市图书存放处
Gotham City Book Depository.
好诶  监视
Yay. Stakeout.
我去买甜甜圈
I'll buy the doughnuts.
这次别买辣热狗了
Just no chili dogs this time, huh?
我把计划告诉巴恩斯
I'll let Barnes know the plan.
把刀送去给盖勒文了
Sent the knife to Galavan.
你最喜欢了  是吧
Your favorite, isn't it?
克洛斯怀特  20年酿
Crosswhite, 20 year.
没错
That's the stuff, all right.
喝一杯吧
Have a taste.
算了  不过谢谢
Nah, I'm-I'm good right now. But thanks.
喝一杯吧  布奇
Have a drink, Butch.
你的调教还是很好使啊
Your conditioning is still working nicely, hmm?
你无法拒绝我
You can't refuse me.
你是我现在唯一能信任的人
You're the only man I can truly trust right now.
你听上去有点疑神疑鬼啊  老大
Starting to sound a little paranoid, boss.
是吗
Am I?
我是要疯了吗
Am I going mad?
怎么能不疯呢
Mm, how could I not
那混蛋抓了我妈妈啊
when that fiend has my mother in his clutches?
再喝一杯吧  布奇
Have another drink, Butch.
或许我是疯了
Maybe I am going mad.
也或许  我找到了盖勒文的软肋
Or maybe I found Galavan's weakness.
是吗
You did?
那把刀  布奇
The knife, Butch.
那把砍残了他先祖的刀
The knife that maimed his ancestor.
盖勒文是来寻仇的
This is a blood feud for Galavan.
他想报复韦恩家族
He wants revenge against the Waynes.
他的行为被情绪左右
He's acting out of emotion.
这一点是可以操纵的
And that can be manipulated.
再喝一杯
Have another drink.
你要去找盖勒文
You are going to go to Galavan
告诉他我疯了
and you're going to tell him I went nuts
我说是你安排了点钞房的突袭
and that I accused you of setting up the count shop raid.
你担心自己性命有危险
You are in fear for your life,
所以想要份工作  懂了吗
and you need a job, got that?
是  老大
Yes, boss.
等你打入了他的组织
Once you're inside his organization,
就找到我妈妈  救出她
you will find my mother and rescue her.
是  老大  但是
Yes, boss. But...
盖勒文很聪明  这招太普通了
Galavan's a smart guy, and that's a basic play.
他绝对不会相信我背叛了你
No way is he gonna buy I turned traitor.
是啊
No.
但他会相信我认为你背叛了我
But he will buy that I think you turned traitor.
只要我们演得像
He'll buy it...
他就会相信
if we sell it right.
喝吧
Drink up.
我们怎么演
How do we sell it?
我已经让他觉得我疑神疑鬼了
I already sold him my paranoia.
但你得来一锤定音
But you're the closer.
我们怎么让你像回事
How do we sell you?
我们怎么让他信任你  同情你
How do we make him trust and feel for you?
我本来还拿不定主意
I wasn't sure.
但瑟莱斯汀和凯勒布给我支了一招
But then Celestine and Caleb told me how.
怎么办
How?
是洋葱提味儿
It's the onions that bring it together.
又甜又酸  是吧
The sweetness and the acid, am I right?
我讨厌做监视
I hate stakeouts.
好警察一半的能力在于
Mmm, half of good police work is the ability
有必要时能干坐着
to sit on one's ass when it's called for.
如果真是那样  你都该当局长了
If that were true, you'd be commissioner.
注意
Heads up.
各小队待命
All units stand by.
可能有情况
We may have something.
收到
Roger.
里面都是旧书  这个简单
So it's all old books in there, so this one's easy.
把凝固汽油撒开  引燃
Just spread the napalm around, spark that thing up
就行了  毫不费力
and go to town. Zero sweat.
这东西让我害怕
This thing scares me.
嗯  那是喷火器  本就该吓人
Yeah, it's a flamethrower, it's meant to be scary.
穿好衣服  把事情搞定
Get suited up and get this done.
还有三个地方要去呢
We got three more spots to hit.
各小队立刻赶往我位置
All units converge on our location. Now.
这就来
Moving in.
-哥谭市警局  -跑
- GCPD! - Run!
快走
Go, go, go!
灰色面包车  正驶离小巷
Gray van leaving the alley.
退后
Get back!
求你
Please!
退后
Get back!
放下
Drop it!
放下武器
Put down the weapon!
-放下武器  -我抓到她了
- Drop the weapon! - I got her!
-放下  -不
- Drop it. - No!
-加勒特  别  -放开我
- Garrett, no! - Let me go!
放开
Let go of it!
不要
No!
放开我
Let go of me!
加勒特
Garrett!
我来  我来
I got him, I got him.
叫救护车  警官受伤
I need an ambulance! Officer down!
布莉姬特  布莉姬特
Bridgit! Bridgit!
快上来
Come on, hurry!
快点  跟我来
Quick, follow me!
-我们去哪  -回家
- Where are we going? - Home.
谢谢
Thanks.
有消息吗
Any news?
还没呢
Not yet.
不过那孩子很坚强  肯定能撑过来
But he's a tough kid, I bet you he makes it.
你哥们来了
Your buddy's here.
一直在跟人握手
Can't stop pressing the flesh.
真会搞公关
Real publicity hound.
这里又没有摄像机
There's no cameras here.
请听好
Your attention, please.
警监
Captain?
卢克·加勒特
Luke Garrett...
-今早5:23去世了  -该死
- passed away at 5:23 a.m. - Damn it.
这不对
It ain't right.
在个小巷里被个怪人烧死
Burned to death in an alley by some weirdo.
他本来会成为个好警察的
He was gonna be a great cop.
他就是个好警察
He was a great cop.
我们会哀悼他
And we will mourn him.
但现在不行
But not now.
现在有个警察杀手逍遥法外
There is a cop killer on the loose.
这我不能容忍
I cannot abide that.
我们要找到杀了我们弟兄的人
We will find the person who killed our brother,
采取一切合法手段
and we will put a stop to them
阻止他们
using every legal method at our disposal.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
你那位警察兄弟死了  我从你的表情看得出
Your fellow officer is dead, I can see it in your face.
是的
He is.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry to hear it.
这个城市的坏人在改变
The bad guys in this town are changing.
他们不再遵守旧规则了
They're not playing by the old rules.
不再遵守任何规则了
Or any rules.
我们需要采取一切手段
We need every method at our disposal.
而且不仅是武力
And I'm not just talking about more guns.
你得去一些地方
You need to go where you need to go,
笼络一些人  好让城市支持你
press who you need the press and have the city back your play.
没错
Correct.
我不知道将来情况会有多糟
I don't know how bad it's gonna get.
但如果你能向我保证
But if you can give me your word...
承诺我们不用单独面对
we won't have to face it alone...
我就背书你
...you'll have my endorsement.
我保证  你会得到一切支持
I promise you, you'll have whatever you need.
克里尔神父
Father Creel.
西奥
Theo.
好久不见
It's been a long time.
你气色不错
You look well.
你也是
As do you.
你把自己沉浸在奢华之中
You've surrounded yourself with luxury.
我得扮演好角色  神父
Well, I have to play the part, Father, and...
你能看到
as you'll see...
已经起效了
...it's paying off.
这么多年了  还如此锋利
Still sharp after all these years.
你抓到韦恩家的男孩了吗
You have the Wayne boy?
还没呢
Not yet.
有些实际问题还有待解决
There are some practical matters that have to be resolved first.
将军之前  还得再下几步棋
A few pieces to arrange on the board before the checkmate.
但快了
But soon.
都快两百年了  我们耐得住性子
After almost 200 years, we can be patient.
救赎之日将近
The day of redemption is at hand.
我们的兄弟此刻就在渡海
Our brothers are crossing the ocean even now.
这座城市前所未见的勇士
Warriors like this city has never known.
哥谭将在鲜血中得到救赎
Gotham will be redeemed in blood.
布鲁斯·韦恩会没命
And Bruce Wayne will die.